<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Armel Kitenge</title>
    <link>https://armelk0.github.io/armel_portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Armel Kitenge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://armelk0.github.io/armel_portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://armelk0.github.io/armel_portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://armelk0.github.io/armel_portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Follow me on these social media platforms.
   Platform URL     Email: armelkitenge@hotmail.com   Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/armel-kitenge-b10708a2/   Twitter: https://twitter.com/Muanango   github: https://github.com/armelk0   Medium: https://medium.com/@muanangoarmel    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Profitable App Profiles for the App Store and Google Play Markets</title>
      <link>https://armelk0.github.io/armel_portfolio/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://armelk0.github.io/armel_portfolio/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>In this project, we are going to be analyzing App profiles for apps in the Google play market and the iTunes App store, in order to determine which is the best kind of app we should be focused on developing as our upcoming product.
Because our company only builds apps that are free to download and install, and our main source of revenue consists of in-app ads, the profitability of any of our apps is highly dependant on the number of users that use our app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Exploring Hacker News Posts</title>
      <link>https://armelk0.github.io/armel_portfolio/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://armelk0.github.io/armel_portfolio/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>In this project, we are going to analyze data from the website Hacker News which is a site started by the startup incubator Y Combinator where user-submitted stories (known as &amp;ldquo;posts&amp;rdquo;) are voted and commented upon, similar to reddit. The original dataset in this project can be found here. However, it has been reduced from almost 300,000 rows to approximatly 20,000 by removing all submissions that did not receive any comment, and then randomly sampling from the remaining submissions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Exploring Ebay Car Sales Data</title>
      <link>https://armelk0.github.io/armel_portfolio/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://armelk0.github.io/armel_portfolio/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>In this project, we are going to work with a dataset of used cars from eBay Kleinanzeigen , a classifieds section of the German eBay website.
The dataset was originally scraped and uploaded to Kaggle. However DataQuest has made a few modifications to the dataset by:
 Sampling 50,000 data points from the full dataset, to ensure the code runs quickly in their hosted environment. Dirtying the dataset a bit more to closely resemble what we would expect from a scraped dataset (the version uploaded to Kaggle was cleaned to be easier to work with).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: Visualizing Earnings Based On College Majors</title>
      <link>https://armelk0.github.io/armel_portfolio/post/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://armelk0.github.io/armel_portfolio/post/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>In this project, we&amp;rsquo;ll be working with a dataset on the job outcomes of students who graduated from college between 2010 and 2012. The original data on job outcomes was released by American Community Survey, which conducts surveys and aggregates the data. FiveThirtyEight cleaned the dataset and released it on their Github repo.
Each row in the dataset represents a different major in college and contains information on gender diversity, employment rates, median salaries, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 5: Cleaning and Analyzing Employee Exit Surveys</title>
      <link>https://armelk0.github.io/armel_portfolio/post/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://armelk0.github.io/armel_portfolio/post/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>In this project, we are going to clean and analyze exit surveys of Department of Education, Training and Employment (DETE) and the Technical and Further Education (TAFE) institute in Queensland, Australia. The exit survey for the TAFE can be found here and the survey for the DETE here.
The objective of this project will be to find out the following :
 Are employees who only worked for the institutes for a short period of time resigning due to some kind of dissatisfaction?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 6: Star Wars Survey</title>
      <link>https://armelk0.github.io/armel_portfolio/post/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://armelk0.github.io/armel_portfolio/post/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>While waiting for Star Wars: The Force Awakens to come out, the team at FiveThirtyEight became interested in answering some questions about Star Wars fans. In particular, they wondered: does the rest of America realize that “The Empire Strikes Back” is clearly the best of the bunch?
The team needed to collect data addressing this question. To do this, they surveyed Star Wars fans using the online tool SurveyMonkey. They received 835 total responses, which we downloaded from their GitHub repository.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>